# Manoela C Dos Santos

Frontend Developer

Maceió, Brazil

aleonamaissac@gmail.com +55 82 996089487 github.com/manoelacs linkedin.com/in/manoelacs/

#### About

I have been working as a front-end developer for five years. During this time, I have assisted companies in migrating their projects to new technologies and building applications from scratch, showcasing my adaptability and technical expertise.

My real strength is my motivation to learn and continually improve myself, which drives me to stay up-to-date and expand my skill set.

I have developed interactive elements that have received positive user feedback, improving engagement in key sections. I have also streamlined workflows by migrating projects to React, making maintenance and updates more straightforward for the team, and reducing development time.

Collaborating with design and product teams, I implemented responsive components, enabling smooth development and timely project completion. Additionally, I have enhanced platform accessibility to make them more inclusive and userfriendly.

# Experience

# • Purple Metrics, Front-end Developer

Jan 2022 – Present

- Participate in the planning of new product features and the validation of candidate features.
- Plan the division of issues for development sprints, alignment of weekly tasks, code review, discussion of tools, and approach to development and testing.
- Tech: ReactJS, TypeScript, CSS, HTML5, SASS, React-query, JestJS, Playwrite, ConfigCat, Git, CircleCI, Kanban, react-test-library

### Slide Box Apresentações LTDA, Front-end Developer

Jul 2021 – Dec 2021

- Spearheaded the development of an innovative platform using Gatsby, a ReactJS-based framework.
- Integrated customizable components from Ant Design, enhanced by less CSS preprocessing.
- Ensured a highly responsive layout adaptable to desktop and mobile devices.
- Tech: ReactJS, JavaScript, TypeScript, Redux, RxJS, HTML5, CSS, SASS, LESS, Styled-components, Git, Scrum.

#### • Inovations Center - EDGE, Front-end Developer

Feb 2021 - Jul 2021

- Actively defined initial product specifications, assembled cross-functional teams, and selected development tools.
- Contributed to the frontend development team using ReactJS, TypeScript, Ant Design, Context API, styled-components, and Adobe XD for design.
- Followed SCRUM methodology with daily stand-up meetings, sprint planning sessions, and retrospectives.
- Tech: ReactJS, Context API, TypeScript, CSS, HTML5, Ant Design, Styled-components, Moment, Git, Scrum.

## Education

# • Federal University of Alagoas State

Computer Science, Bachelor 2013 – 2021

- Key areas of expertise:
  - \* Data Structures and Algorithms: Fundamental understanding of data structures, strong understanding of algorithms and algorithmic complexity, and problem-solving skills.
  - \* Programming and Software Development: Proficiency in multiple programming languages (JavaScript, Python, Java, C, etc.), software design, development, and testing, knowledge of software development methodologies (Agile, Scrum, Kanban, etc.), and version control systems like Git.
  - \* Web Development: Frontend (HTML, CSS, JavaScript, TypeScript, React) development.

# Skills

• Problem solving, flexibility, adaptability, creativity, teamwork, self-discipline, effective communication, and selfmotivation.

• HTML/CSS, JavaScript/TypeScript, React, Jest/Playwrite, Responsive Design, SASS/LESS, Scrum, GitHub, CircleCI, GitHub Actions.

#### Licenses and Certifications

- Robot Framework with PlayWright and GitHub actions (Udemy, 2023)
- Microfrontends with React: A complete Developer's Guide (Udemy, 2023)
- Languages:
  - 2024, IELTS General English (B2)
  - 2022, Language Exchange in South Africa (B1-B2)